Igor Vodchits

Toronto, Ontario M8V 0C7 | +1(437)557-03-78 ivodchits.ca@gmail.com
WWW: www.linkedin.com/in/igorvodchits-51995a161



Highly-skilled Programmer with 6 years in Game Development who values the creative process and connections the most. Advanced knowledge of Unity game engine and C# programming language. Exceptional communication and problem-solving skills. Proficient in both slow-paced development and rapid prototyping.

Skills

- Unity
- C#
- Game Development
- Object-Oriented Programming
- Performance Optimization
- .NET development
- Teamwork and Collaboration
- Problem-Solving
- Effective Communication
- Prototyping

Work History

May 2022 - February 2024

Game Programmer

Gameloft Toronto, Toronto, Canada

- Worked on multiple unannounced projects for various platforms
- Created countless essential game systems, like 3C or tutorial framework, for different games
- Tech stack included Unity, C#, C++, Lua and other proprietary libraries and frameworks
- Successfully implemented uNode and Animancer tools as efficient alternative to Unity Animator, as well as Nova framework instead of Unity UI
- Helped deliver smooth launch of Fresh Planet's game "SongPop Party" on Nintendo Switch
- Judged students' works from technical perspective during XP summit showcase.

December 2021 -March 2022

Unity Developer

IT Territory, Moscow, Russia

- Developed mobile multiplayer auto-battler called Castle Duels
- Created tools for game designers and artists
- Improved gameplay and performance

- Developed new features
- Ensured smooth and efficient UI animation.

November 2020 -November 2021

Unity Developer

GD Company, Moscow, Russia

- Created multiplayer top-down shooter prototype with tagging mechanics that allowed players to convert opponents into one's own team
- That prototype later evolved into Grand Wars: Mafia City, multiplayer game featuring region captures and massive brawls with AI companion mobsters
- Implemented countless essential and quality-of-life features, including projectiles, region capturing, tutorial, and others
- Created efficient algorithms for Al-controlled characters to follow players and help them in combat utilizing different tactics.

December 2019 -November 2020

Unity Developer

Banzai. Games, Moscow, Russia

- Created various fundamental features for a prototype of a multiplayer PvP shooter with fighting elements called "Spine"
- Wrote complex shaders, developed new gameplay features, created editor tools for game designers
- Helped shape the game and experiment with different combat and animation approaches.

August 2018 -November 2019

Unity Developer

Lightmap, Moscow, Russian Federation

- Developed client side of a mobile multiplayer first-person shooter Bitter End
- Effectively used game development and teamwork skills to create gameplay features and tools for designers
- Came up with performant solutions for in-game abilities, projectiles, jump pads and multiple other areas
- Improved network state interpolation system
- Utilized Photon knowledge to ensure stable P2P connection
- Created a cool UI effect for the ability cards menu.

July 2017 - August 2018

Unity Developer

Interactive Moolt, Moscow, Russian Federation

- Developed the client side for a farming/city builder hybrid called "Fairy Town"
- Implemented server-side logic using Java
- Optimized the game for WebGL and for mobile platforms
- Came up with an algorithm for generating in-game orders and quests
- Integrated 2D and 2D assets using both plugins and native Unity capabilities
- Sustained network communication using WebSocket protocol
- Learned to work effectively in a small team with short development lifecycles.

Education

June 2018

Bachelor's degree in Computer Science

National University of Science And Technology "MISIS" at Moscow, Russia

Websites, Portfolios, Profiles

https://ivodchits.github.io/portfolio/

Languages

English

Additional Information

For me nothing can compare with the joy of shaping something into existence. I see my future in a role that would require both coding and soft skills.

My personal pet projects include many prototypes such as:

- a digital version of a board game Small World of Warcraft;
- an endless runner game with shooting mechanics;
- a multiplayer board game with mechanics similar to tabletop Game of Thrones;
- a twin-stick shooter with local coop and survival bits;
- a drinking game for programmers where your goal is to write JS code that controls a robot on the arena while your opponent does the same. Each time your robot dies the game makes you drink.

On a personal note I try my best to be a decent person. I play video games, chess and guitar in my spare time. Fascinated by all the new technologies rapidly emerging in the recent years, such as AI and VR.